# Doug Watro

DougWatro@gmail.com

DougWatro.com

#### **LANGUAGES**

HTML5

CSS / SASS

JAVASCRIPT / ES6 / JSX

JAVA

C + +

**C**#

#### **SKILLS**

OOP

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPMENT

GAME DEVELOPMENT

UX DESIGN

RESPONSIVE WEB DEVELOPMENT

CODE OPTIMIZATION

# SOFTWARE / FRAMEWORKS

REACT / REDUX

VISUAL STUDIOS

GIT

ATOM

WORDPRESS

NPM

BOOTSTRAP

ADOBE CC

#### **GOALS**

To learn all I can about fullstack web development, and keep on the bleeding edge of new technologies.

Use my experiences in computer science and game development to offer a different perspective on UX and the art of web programming.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### DESIGN ASSISTANT | MAGIC SPELL STUDIOS

FEBRUARY 2014 - AUGUST 2014

Conceptualized and designed 3D game levels to be integrated within a larger game world. Work among a team of 20 to design the overall direction of the project. Designed small levels to be used in promotional material.

## LEVEL DESIGNER/3D ARTIST | IGM GRAD DEPARTMENT

WINTER - SPRING 2015

Worked with a team of grad students to assist them in completing their capstone project. Acted as the sole level designer for their 3D topdown action tower defense game. Worked with other artist to model and texture assets when needed.

#### INDECISION BETA APP RELEASE | GOOGLE PLAY STORE

LATE 2016 - EARLY 2017

Designed, programmed, and began public beta tests of an Android App on the Google Play Store.

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER | WEB FORUM COMMUNITY

May 2020 - PRESENT

Work with a team of other front-end and back-end developers to refactor, redesign, crush bugs, and add features to a forum community site serving over 10,000 unique users.

### **EDUCATION**

ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY 2012 - 2017 BS | GAME DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT